Azad Mamiyev

Android Developer

azad.mamiyev.1998@gmail.com | +447867742288 | Bristol, United Kingdom https://www.linkedin.com/in/azadmamiyev/ | https://github.com/siftoshka

PROFILE

An Android Developer with 3+ years of experience in developing, designing, and maintaining Android apps in multiple industries such as product tech companies, startups, and consulting agencies. Experienced in delivering features via A/B Testing, building Bitrise pipelines, writing tests, refactoring, and optimizing existing code. Currently working and based in Bristol, United Kingdom

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Android Developer, Cookpad &

- Migrated a flow of onboarding screens from XML Views to Jetpack Compose. Bristol, United Kingdom

- Working on building, editing, and optimizing Bitrise pipelines

- Covered features with unit, integration, and E2E tests
- Assisting iOS Engineers with migration to use generated paths using CreateAPI
- Exoplayer improvements (Better Buffering, Audio, New Features) by releasing via A/B testing. The wait time for video buffering decreased by 3 times.
- Release manager responsibilities: Releasing updates, Monitoring Crashlytics

Android Developer, ByAllMeans *⊘*

Aug 2020 - Jul 2022 - Developed chat-related features with reactions Prague, Czech Republic

- Actively participated in product management, design & QA team meetings
- Implemented Google Play Billing Library
- Maintained the existing project with improvements to user experience

Intern Android Developer, CRBN Tech &

May 2019 - Aug 2019 - Developed a custom app integrating QR Code Reader and Music Player Baku, Azerbaijan

- Partnered with peers to create an outstanding user experience

EDUCATION

MSc., Web & Software Engineering, Czech Technical University in Prague ∂ Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

- Experienced in genetic algorithms and management information systems.

- Well-versed in patterns, user interface design, and networking.

BSc., Compter Science, Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry University *⊘*

- Gained experience working on group projects

Sep 2015 - Jun 2019

Prague, Czech Republic

Baku, Azerbaijan

Aug 2022 - present

SKILLS

Kotlin, Java, Swift, Jetpack Compose, Kotlin Flow and Coroutines, RxJava, Rest API, GraphQL, OkHttp, OpenAPI, Retrofit, Jetpack Libraries, Firebase Tools, SqlDelight, Koin, Dagger Hilt, Timber, jUnit, Espresso, Kaspresso, Mockito

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Habitube, Movie Library App ⊘

- Successfully facilitated seamless migration from legacy technologies (Java, RxJava, XML Views) to modern development technologies (Kotlin, Coroutines, Compose) for end users
- Designed elegant and user-friendly interfaces using Figma

LANGUAGES

English (IELTS B2), Turkish (Limited Working Proficiency), Russian (Native), Azerbaijani (Native)